I see blue, I see blue
Looking up at the big, clear sky
As I feel, as I feel
Fresh cut grass right here where I lie
Playing a fun game of hide-and-seek
From the sunflower field, take a peek
Then we'll blow, then we'll blow
Round, round soap bubbles, you and I
Kobato.
Dou sureba iin dakke?
Atarimae no kototte itsumo
Muzukashii na
Ureshii toki waratte
Suki na toki ni utaitai dake
Na no ni
Itsuka negai wa kanau to
Demo "itsuka" tte dore kurai?
Machikirenai yo
123! no aizu de ryoute hirogete
Zenshin ni hikari wo atsumete
Doko ni aru no?
Oshiete, watashi ni dekiru koto
Meippai kizu tsuite
Seiippai hashitte
Nan juu kai koronde naite
Sore de mo mada
Akireru kurai
Ashita wo shinjiteru
I see white, I see white
...The Boy's Organ Days.
Chasing clouds as they drift away
And there!
Let's all run, let's all run
Me and my friends, 'cause we love to play
You've got a lot of energy first thing in the
morning in this darn hot weather!
Me and my friends, 'cause we love to play
What is that song?
I learned it from the children at Yomogi
Kindergarten. Isn't it a fun song?
When we get to the...
Huh?
That was frightening!
I thought I was going to fall.
Would you be quiet?!
Oh! Good morning!
It's Sunday morning.
What the heck are you doing?
I-I'm hanging out the bedding to air.
It's such a beautiful day.
Man, can't you do anything
without causing a major stir?
He's not nice.
Dobato...
Ioryogi-san!
Are you okay?
Do I look okay?
No I'm not!
Like I keep telling you, in this
world I am a stuffed doll!
Don't expect miracles!
I'm sorry.
See you later.
Take care, now. Have a nice day.
Yes, ma'am.
The guy Ms. Chitose is seeing off.
That's Fujimoto, isn't it?
I think that's pretty obvious.
It's strange.
What is?
Fujimoto was just in the next room,
and now he's already out the front door.
He sure is a busy man.
Maybe...
Maybe there are two Fujimoto's.
It's not like we're in a suspense movie!
Kobato, what was that noise?
Oh, oh, nothing!
Where are you going?
Yomogi Kindergarten.
It's closed today.
It's a nice day. I thought I'd go
and hang out the futons.
Hey Kobato. Do you know what you're doing?
What do you mean?
What is your purpose in coming here?
To fill the bottle with kompeito.
Well if you know that, don't you think there are
other things you could be doing on a Sunday?
But...
Right now, I just want to do what I
can to help Yomogi Kindergarten.
I report! Regarding Yomogi Kindergarten!
The former principal was apparently
tricked into borrowing money!
Former principal?
Yes. Sayaka Okiura's father.
He died two years ago.
Looks like a real bad bunch who tricked him.
Not only that, one of them seems to
be a relative of Sayaka Okiura.
Ms. Sayaka.
Kobato?
What's the matter?
Today's a holiday.
Yes.
I came to air out everybody's futons.
Futons?
Yes. It's such a nice day.
It sure is a nice day.
I didn't even notice.
Okay. Let's hang them out together.
Yes!
Chisato's really happy. She says she's glad
that a nice girl like you has moved in.
I enjoy living there. Ms. Chisato and Chiho
and Chise are so much fun to be with.
How about Fujimoto, next door?
Has he been mean to you?
Well sometimes he's mean and then
sometimes he isn't. I don't know.
I don't understand him.
It many not seem like it,
but Fujimoto is a kind person.
He's been that way since he was a small child.
Fujimoto as a small child?
That's hard to imagine.
Want to see a picture?
Sorry to keep you waiting. Here it is.
Look.
Wow! He's tiny.
This is Fujimoto?
Yes. We took this picture the first
day he arrived here.
Fujimoto was a Yomogi Kindergarten student?
No, no he wasn't.
Fujimoto was an orphan.
Orphan?
What's an orphan?
Oh um... An orphan is a child who doesn't
have a mother or a father or a home.
Huh?
If you don't intend to care for her
to the end, don't get involved.
If you're only taking care of it
half-heartedly to satisfy yourself,
you're just as guilty as the
people who abandoned it.
That's why...
He said those things.
Kobato?
Please tell me more. I'd like to know
more about Fujimoto's childhood.
All right.
That was about fourteen years ago.
My father took Fujimoto in.
I'm home, Sayaka.
This is Kiyokazu Fujimoto,
the boy I was telling you about.
Fujimoto, this is my daughter Sayaka.
Hi, I'm Sayaka. Nice to meet you Fujimoto.
I know! A picture! We need a picture
to mark this moment! Right?
I'll go and get the camera right away.
Where'd I put that camera?
Are you ready?
Everybody say "Yomo-giii."
And from that day on, Fujimoto was to live here.
Fujimoto looks angry.
Yeah maybe. When he first arrived,
he always had this look on his face.
He wouldn't talk to anyone, either.
Not even to you?
No. He was always alone.
We tried introducing him to the children.
At first they were interested in him.
But he never paid attention to anyone,
so they stopped coming near him.
He didn't seem to have any
friends at school, either.
He was the type that just wouldn't let anyone
close to him, so perhaps it couldn't be helped.
Hello.
You're supposed to say, "I'm home"!
I don't like Fujimoto.
Me neither!
Bye-bye Sayaka.
Bye. See you tomorrow.
Fujimoto, you like the organ?
Fujimoto?!
Sayaka!
See you tomorrow!
Fujimoto...
Free Sampling Campaign
New Product!
Anybody like some ice cold beer?
We're giving away free samples.
Can I have one?
Here you go.
Would you like some really good beer?
We're presently conducting a campaign.
Um...
Is this free?
Y-Yes. It's a new product.
Please try some.
Thank you very much.
Shuichiro will be so happy.
It was a beautiful summer day like today.
It's my turn next.
No it isn't. It's my turn!
Kuri, you already went.
Come on now, no fighting.
Everybody wait your turn.
Yes ma'am,
Do you think they'll blossom soon?
Why sure.
I'm sure they'll blossom beautifully, because
you all have taken such good care of them.
Really?!
Really.
Yeah!
Well then everybody. Tidy up before you play.
Yes ma'am!
Hello.
Tomo, are you all right?
You know what? A ball came flying.
Tomo got surprised and fell over.
Sayaka!
Tomo, did you get hurt? Are you okay?
Why did you push me?
Sorry man.
I didn't think you'd really fall.
This isn't funny. I'm all covered in dirt.
Never mind. Hurry up and go find the ball.
It's all because of your lousy pass.
I know.
Darn! It won't come off.
Why is it so wet here?
Hey!
What are you guys doing?!
Oh, well... our ball came in and uh...
Do you realize how dangerous that is?!
You almost hit this child!
But it didn't hit her, did it?
What are you so upset about?
And get out of the garden, now!
Huh?
We planted these sunflowers together and
have been taking great care of them!
We've been looking forward to seeing them
blossom, very soon!
Here's your ball!
I want you to apologize to this girl,
and all the children. Then leave!
Um. That was our fault.
Sorry about that.
Your trap was too big.
Then you shouldn't have passed it way out
there. How do you expect me to reach it?
Sayaka.
The sunflower...
It'll be okay.
It just got hurt a little.
We hold it up like this...
Water it every day and it'll bloom for sure.
Really?
Yes.
I see white, I see white
Chasing clouds as they drift away
Let's all run, let's all run
Me and my friends, 'cause we love to play
When we get to the top of the hill
We can see everything, what a thrill
Let's go look, let's go look
Let's find wonderful things today
Are you aware that Fujimoto has a lot of jobs?
Yes, I do.
He delivers pizzas, does bicycle-courier,
delivers newspapers, and a whole lot more.
That many?
Yes. He's helping in every way he can
to pay back kindergarten loans.
He's doing it for the kindergarten?
That's right. And he seems to be
studying until very late every night.
He says he wants to become a lawyer.
I'm worried he's going to make himself sick.
Soft, and a nice scent!
It's the smell of the sun.
The sun?
That's right.
When you hang futons out,
they smell like the sun.
Well, that's what my father told me anyway.
So tomorrow, everybody gets
to take a nap with the sun.
That's right.
Did I say something funny?
No. Not at all. It's wonderful, isn't it?
Yes. I'm looking forward to tomorrow.
Shall we bring them in, then?
Yes!
Thank you for coming today.
Be careful on your way home.
Yes. See you tomorrow.
The sun...
It's Fujimoto!
Welcome home!
Hey, will you play the organ again?
Yeah, play it for us, please.
Hey! It's Fujimoto!
Yeah, it is!
Welcome home!
Hello.
I uh... I...
I'm home!
Come on, Fujimoto, the organ, the organ.
Hurry, hurry...
I see red, I see red
Sunset color, pretty as a poem
Let us walk, let us walk
It's that time of day, no time to roam
If tomorrow we see the sun
Let's meet again for play and fun
Bye for now, bye for now
It's time to go, yes, there is your home
See that?! There's no increase
in the number of kompeito!
Uhh... but, but, I wanted to take out the futons.
I wanted to be of help to the kindergarten.
Not just the futons, you hung me out there too.
I'm sorry.
Kobato. Ioryogi-san.
I thought it might be you.
Perfect timing. I was about to
bring this over to you.
I-Is this allowed?!
Yes. I have one in the fridge for Shuichiro.
Well then thank you.
Wasn't that nice, Ioryogi-san?
Okay, bottoms up!
No wait. I'm going to fight the urge now
and enjoy it before I go to bed!
Kohaku, you're always properly watering the
trees in your garden. I'm impressed.
It's about all I can do for Shuichiro.
But every little bit I can do for
him makes me feel good.
I'm happy too, whenever I'm able
to help Yomogi Kindergarten.
Yes. Happiness is being able to
help those who are dear to you.
Those who are dear.
Yomogi Kindergarten is very
dear to Fujimoto, isn't it?
I should think so, seeing the number
of jobs he does for them.
To me too.
I feel...
Huh?
I feel that Yomogi Kindergarten
is very dear to me.
I want to be able to help Ms. Sayaka
and the others as much as I can!
Kobato is ready!
Why do I get the feeling we're heading
in the wrong direction again?
Hello Kobato.
Welcome home.
Hi, I'm back.
Oh! Fujimoto!
You were a very cute child!
And, and when you were small, you had trouble
reaching the pedals of the organ, right?!
How do you know that stuff?!
Ms. Sayaka showed me pictures of you today!
I wanna see them!
Me too!
I'd like to see them too.
Tiny Fujimoto!
Not you too, Ms. Chisato!
He's tiny and cute, but has a
big pout on his face.
Not you too, Ms. Chisato!
He's tiny and cute, but has a
big pout on his face.
Don't say another word!
Tell us more!
Um... What shall I do now?
Then later, when he's not around.
Hito wa mina tonde mitai no ni
Juuryoku ni damasareterunda
Dare mo honto wa toberunda yo
Ano ko ga anna ni kanashisou na no wa
Jibun no kage wo
Dokoka ni wasurete kichatta kara kamo
Sore nara
"Arigatou," tte kimi ni ietara
"Arigatou," tte kimi ga waraeba
Ittari kitari ureshiku naru
Kimi ga shiawase ni naru
Shinpai nante iranai yo
Issho ni iru kara
Ureshikuttemo namida ga deru nante
Fushigi da
Next episode
...Detective Kobato Hanato.
Fushigi da
Next episode
...Detective Kobato Hanato.